再试一次
Try again.
托宾  声音没停
Tobin, it's not stopping.
发射信号弹  听到了吗
Light it up. You hear me?
托宾
Tobin!
-米琼恩  -我来
- Michonne. - Got it.
该死  有一半
Shit! Shit! It was half.
天啊  不止一半
Jesus, it was more than half.
我们得赶在它们前面
We just gotta stay ahead of them.
它们走  我们跑
They walk, we run.
-瑞克  -我在
- Rick! - I'm here.
后面什么情况
What's going on back there?
一半行尸改变了方向
Half of them broke off.
它们朝亚历山大去了
They're going toward Alexandria.
朝你们去了吗
Towards you?
我们跑在前面  有喇叭声
We ran ahead. There's a horn or something.
声音很大  从东边传来的  一直不停
Loud, coming from the east. It's not stopping.
我要踩油门折回了
I'm gonna gas it up, turn back.
我们来处理  你继续前行
We have it. You keep going.
他们需要我们的帮助
They're gonna need our help.
必须让尸群继续前进
Gotta keep the herd moving.
如果家里出事  就不用了
Not if it's going down, we don't.
如果剩余的尸群也掉头
The rest of that herd turns around,
家里的情况只会更糟
the bad back there gets worse.
达里尔
Daryl?
我听见了
Yeah, I heard you.
尼古拉斯
Nicholas.
你没事吧
You okay?
是我的脚踝
It's my ankle.
好吧  搭着我  走吧
All right, come on. Grab on. Let's go.
快
Come on.
声音是从家那边传来的
It's coming from back home.
-肯定是  -是他做的
- It has to be. - He did this.
他带我们来这里送死
He brought us all out here to die.
-他杀了卡特  -卡特本来就必死无疑
- He killed Carter. - Carter was dead already.
现在家里有麻烦了  我们也死定了
Now they're in trouble back there and we're done.
-我们死定了  -冷静点
- We're good as dead. - Hey, calm down.
你说些什么呢
What the hell are you talking about?
我们死定了  都是因为他
We are done. And it's 'cause of him.
闭嘴  快跑
Shut up and move.
快点
Come on.
该死
Damn it.
听好了  这是新计划
All right, listen up. Here's the new plan.
我回去开房车  从雷丁路绕过森林
I go back, get the RV, circle around the woods on Redding.
我会赶在它们前面抵达
I'll get in front of them before they get there.
我可以再次引走它们
I can lead them away again.
房车离这里有一英里  我跟你一起去
RV's a mile back. I can go with you.
我去吧  你们回家
I'll handle it. Just get home.
他们也许需要你们
They might need you there.
格伦  米琼恩
Glenn, Michonne.
不管遇到什么  格杀勿论
If something's in front of you, you kill it.
不用躲藏和等待  一直往家走
No hiding, no waiting. You keep going.
我跟你一起去  你一个人做不到的
I'm going with you. You can't do this on your own.
-格伦  我能做到  -你得帮我
- Glenn, I can do this. - You need to help me.
-我们得把这些人带回去  -没错
- We've got to get these people back. - Yeah.
事实是  他们未必能全活着回去
Thing is, they aren't all gonna make it.
-瑞克  -你们努力救他们  尽力了就行
- Rick. - You try to save them, you try,
但假如他们跟不上  你们就接着走
but they can't keep up, you keep going.
你们必须得这样  你们要确保自己回去
You have to. You make sure you get back.
天啊
Oh, God!
喇叭声停了  很好
The horn stopped. Good.
一路平安
Get back safe.
《行尸走肉》
我们在它们前面了  十分钟的路程
We're ahead of it. 10 minutes.
也许是二十分钟
20 minutes, maybe.
我们保持这个速度  就能安全回家
We all keep up the pace, we all get back home.
假如有人跟不上
So if we don't,
那就死定了  是不是
that's it, huh?
我们都不知道家里什么情况
We don't even know what's waiting for us.
没事的  墙不是白建的
It's gonna be okay. We have walls for a reason.
那个声音  也许有人冲进去了
That sound. Maybe someone plowed right through.
也许我们回去发现一切都被毁了
Maybe we're walking back to nothing.
闭嘴  我老婆还在那里呢
Shh, my wife's back there.
我的也在
Mine, too.
听着  别担心出什么事了
Look, don't worry about what's gone wrong.
想想现在怎么办吧
Figure out how to make this go right.
我们前进的方向和其他东西一样
We're moving in the same direction everything else is.
我们会碰上一些东西的
We're gonna catch up with something.
我们会碰上很多东西的
We're gonna catch up with a lot of things
然后我们会干掉他们
and we're gonna end them.
我们别无选择
We have no choice.
我们得继续前进
We gotta keep going forward.
待在这里
Stay here.
没有必要别开枪
Don't shoot unless you have to.
来吧  那是我们的
Come on. That's us.
斯特奇斯
Sturgess!
我知道这意味着什么
I know what it means.
我们得继续前进  是吧
We gotta keep moving, right?
我们走了有五英里了吗
Hey, we gone five miles out yet?
差不多吧
Give or take some yardage.
为什么这么问
You got a reason for asking?
在下一个十字路口  我们就掉头回去
Next intersection we're gonna spin around and go back.
计划是再走十五英里啊
The plan is to go 15 more.
没错  我要改变计划  五英里就够了
Yeah, I'm gonna change that. Five's gonna have to work.
目标是二十英里
The magic number's 20.
那才是我们的任务
That's the mission.
那是为了确保
That's making sure
它们在不死的余生中去攻击虚弱的浣熊
they're off munching on infirm raccoons the rest of their undead lives
而不是来吃我们
instead of any of us.
你想走的话  我们没法拦你
You want to go, we can't stop you.
但没有你的话  它们也许会干掉我们
But without you, they could stop us.
(亚历山大  可持续生活的开始)
不会的  我对你们有信心
Nah, I got faith in you.
-达里尔  -别这样  兄弟
- Daryl! - Don't do it, man!
-我能看下吗  -请吧
- Can I take a look? - Please?
很糟吗
Is it bad?
跟你预料的差不多
It's about what you'd expect.
我可没料到这个
Huh, didn't expect this.
你结婚多久了
How long you been married?
三个月
Three months.
灾变前她并不是我妻子
She wasn't my wife from before.
你们怎么认识的
How'd you meet?
早些时候
It was early on.
亚伦找到了我
Aaron found me.
我独自一人  一无所有
I was alone, lost everything.
举目无亲
everyone,
迷失自我  我没有疯
myself, I-- I wasn't crazy.
只是内心放弃了
I just gave up on being someone,
变成行尸走肉了
an actual person.
懂我的意思吗
Know what I mean?
我懂
I do.
回社区的路上  我们发现了贝琪
We found Betsy on the way back to the community.
在我自暴自弃的时候
She still saw me
她仍看到了真正的我
after I thought I was dead and gone,
她是我的第一个朋友
she was my first friend.
然后她变成了我的爱人
Then she was more.
也让我变得更好
She made me more.
甚至比灾变前更好
Even better than how I used to be.
如果我能回去  我希望能跟她道别
But if I could make it back, I'd want to say good-bye.
告诉她
Tell her...
能在末世与她相遇
finding her in all this,
意味着一切
that was everything.
我们得停下来给他包扎一下
We need to stop and bandage him up.
不  继续走吧  我很好
No, we keep moving. I'm okay.
要是不止血  你就不会"很好"了
You won't be if we don't stop your bleeding.
我们找个地方
We'll find a place.
不能在露天停留太久
Can't stop out in the open too long.
走吧
Come on.
先检查一下这些车是否能开
Let's check if these cars work first.
看能否开车回去
See if they can get us back.
我跟他们待在一起
I'll stay with them.
听着  我是想回家
Listen, I need to get home,
但我不会抛下他们
but I'm not leaving them behind.
我们给斯科特包扎一下  然后就走
We patch Scott up, we get going.
瑞克虽然那么说
Rick knows what he knows.
但我们领先于尸群
We're ahead of the herd.
现在可能领先了半小时
Maybe half an hour now.
我们可以停留  我们能回去的
We can stop. We can make it.
还有一半路就到家了  对吗
This is halfway home, right?
是的
Yeah.
就是在这发生的
This is where it happened.
我在拖拉机店那里说过
I said it at the dealership.
我和艾登不知道我们在做什么
Me and Aiden didn't know what we were doing.
就是你死去的那个同伴吗
The people on your crew who died?
他们并不害怕
They weren't afraid.
我们却怕极了
We were.
不走运
No luck.
我们得步行回去了
We have to stay on foot.
尼古拉斯来过这
Nicholas was here last.
他可以给我们带路
He can show us the way.
好
Uh, okay.
好的
All right.
车都不能开
There's no cars.
我扶你  我扶你
I got you. I got you.
天啊
Oh, Jesus.
斯特奇斯
Sturgess?
他抛下了我们
He left us behind.
尸群在那边
Herd's that way.
糟了
Shit.
尼古拉斯
Nicholas.
我们保持安静
We stay quiet,
给斯科特和安妮包扎一下
patch Scott and Annie up,
然后离开这里
get out of here.
小巷里和街上的行尸
Those walkers in the alley and down the street,
堵住了出城的路
they're blocking the way out of town.
我们不能正面对抗  尤其是以现在的状况
We can't take 'em on, not in the shape that we're in.
有必要的话我们得把它们引走
We'll have to lead them away if we have to.
近来这招可真有效呢
Because that's been working well lately.
我在努力想办法
I'm trying here.
我不会放弃的
I'm not giving up.
是啊  暂时还没呢
Yeah, not yet.
我在想
Hey, I was thinking,
如果能有办法引走即将到来的尸群
if we can find a way to distract the herd coming in,
它们就不会去社区了
then they won't make it back to the community.
怎么做
How?
烧掉一栋楼
Burn one of the buildings.
越多越好
Hopefully more.
它们会被吸引  止步于此
They'll get drawn to it and they'll stop here.
这需要好一阵子
It's gonna take some time.
我去办  你陪着他们
I'll do it. You stay with them.
是我的主意  我去做
It's my plan. It's on me.
你有妻子  格伦
You have a wife, Glenn.
所以我才这么做
That's why I'm doing this.
你得护送大家回去
You've got to get everybody back.
只有你能做到
You're the one who can.
如果我很久未归  你就走
If I take too long, you just go.
我不会抛下你的
I'm not leaving without you.
-不能这样  -我们社区见
- That is not the way this works. - I will meet you there.
如果我被困住了
If I get stuck out here,
我会想办法告诉你们我还好
I'll find some way to show you guys I'm okay.
我们都有自己的职责
We all have a job to do.
有间饲料库
There's a feed store.
很老  里面有很多干的东西
It's old. A lot of dry stuff inside.
应该很易燃
It should go up easy.
我和你一起去
I'll go with you.
我可以画地图
I can-- I can draw a map.
不
No.
你领路
You lead the way.
我得先去做一件事
Just gotta do one thing first.
瑞克  我是格伦
Rick, it's Glenn.
我们在绿标记偏东五度的小镇上
We're in a town five degrees east of the green marker.
如果你在二十分钟内
If you get around on Redding
从雷丁路绕过去  你就能赶上
in the next 20 minutes, you should be good.
这是我们领先尸群的时间
I think that's how far we're ahead of the herd.
我准备放火引走它们
I'm gonna try to set a fire and distract them.
你要是没看到烟  那它们还是会朝你那边去
If you don't see smoke, they're still coming your way.
我得挂了
I got to go.
祝你好运  笨蛋
Good luck, dumbass.
这能让你撑回医务室
That'll keep you going until we get you back to the infirmary.
安妮  我会帮你找一根拐杖的
Annie, I'm gonna figure out a crutch for you.
别管我了
Just leave me.
说什么
What?
我在拖你们后腿
I'm slowing you down.
我们还会遇到更多行尸
We're gonna hit more roamers.
就这么简单
It's that simple.
别管我了
Leave me.
别管我们了
Leave us.
不行
No.
你们照顾我太愚蠢了
It's stupid for you guys to wait on me.
这样我们都会死的
We'll all go down.
伙计  醒醒吧
Come on, man, wake up.
你现在不想抛下我们
You don't want to do it now,
但在外面不要犹豫
you do it out there.
要是我们又陷入困境  你们就跑
We get into trouble again, you run.
-头也不要回  -不  要走就一起走
- And you don't look back. - No, if we go, we go together.
我们会一如既往地互相照顾
We got each other's backs just like always.
我们不会抛弃别人的
Okay, we don't leave people behind.
这不是我们的风格
Not us.
没人要抛弃谁
No one is leaving anyone behind.
我来帮你找点支撑物  安妮
I'm gonna find something for you, Annie.
你对我有什么意见吗
Do you have a problem with me?
我只是在关心我的人
I'm just looking out for my people.
你觉得我不关心吗
And you think that I'm not?
我听到瑞克说的话了
Look, I heard what Rick said.
哪一段
Which part?
他们未必能全活下来
How they wouldn't all make it.
"他们"说的是我们  不是你们
They meaning us and not you.
如果我们跟不上  你们就该丢下我们
How you should leave us behind if we can't keep up.
格伦为了你和其他人在外面冒着生命危险
Glenn is out there risking his life for you and for everyone else
我也还在这里
and I'm still here,
我不明白你到底在胡说什么
so I don't know what the hell you're talking about.
情况会越来越糟  我们走着瞧
Things are gonna get worse and then we'll see.
对  走着瞧
Yeah, we will.
瑞克之所以说那些话
Rick said what he said
是因为有时你别无选择
because sometimes you don't have a choice.
我们不是这样行事的
That is not how we do it.
那是因为你们从来没有陷入过绝境
Because you've never had to do it any other way.
你们从没真正地经历过
You haven't been through it, not really.
-米琼恩...  -不像瑞克
- Michonne-- - Not like Rick.
瑞克和我都曾在外生存
Rick was out there. I was out there.
我们懂  你们不懂
We know, you don't.
但如果你不吸取经验
But if you don't learn,
你就会死  我们也会
you will die, we will.
我从一开始就一直在出外勤
I've been doing runs from the start, okay?
-我知道外面的情况  -你杀过人没有
- I know what it's like. - Have you ever had to kill people
因为他们已经杀了你的朋友们
because they had already killed your friends
接下来就会来杀了你
and were coming for you next?
你有没有做过一些
Have you ever done things
事后让你自己都惧怕自己的事
that made you feel afraid of yourself afterward?
你是否曾全身都是血
Have you ever been covered in so much blood
但你却不知道那到底是你的血
that you didn't know if it was yours
还是行尸的  或是你朋友们的
or walkers' or your friends'?
那你就不懂
Then you don't know.
等等
Wait.
这个该我来
It should be me.
他之前是我小队里的
He was on my crew.
他叫威尔
His name was Will.
他才十九岁
He was 19.
我们丢下了他
We left him behind.
你不再是从前的你了
You're not that guy anymore.
你现在在这
you are here now.
你不再是从前的你了
You are not that guy anymore.
好的
Okay.
糟了
Shit.
是家那边吗
Is that home?
我们得赶快走了
We need to go now.
好了  好了  走吧
Okay. Okay, let's go.
快点
Come on.
我们得赶快走了
We gotta go now.
是之前街上和小巷里的那些行尸
The ones from down the street and in the alley,
它们被枪声吸引走了
they're getting drawn by the gunfire.
等它们走光  我们就去饲料库
Soon as they clear, we head for the feed store.
在那之前  我们先别动  保持安静
Till then we sit tight, keep quiet.
(贝琪  亲爱的  如果你在看这张纸条  那说明我没能活着回去)
(你会回家的)
它们听到了
They heard that.
它们知道我们在里面了
They know we're in here now.
我们没办法等它们走光了
We can't wait them out.
尸群很快就会过来
The herd, it's gonna be here any minute.
怎么了
What?
它们已经来了
They're coming.
快走
Go!
快点
Come on!
饲料库在哪
Where's the feed store?
-快走  在小镇另一头  能试试  -不行
- Go! The other end of town. We can try-- - We can't.
格伦说我们必须走
Glenn said we got to go. We go now.
快跑
Just run!
跑啊
Go!
就在前面  点着了就走
It's just up ahead. We light it up and we go.
肯定还有别的楼
There's gotta be another building.
我们得走了
We gotta go.
在哪
Where?!
-尼古拉斯  -这边
- Nicholas! - This way.
-在这边  -快走  快走
- This-- this way. - Go! Go!
你先过去  我们再帮斯考特
You go over first, and then we'll help Scott.
不行  它们来了  快走吧
No, they're coming. Just go.
都翻过去  快点
We're doing this. Come on.
快点
Come on!
不
No!
该死
Damn it.
我们必须走了
We gotta go.
我们必须走了  我们别无选择
We gotta keep going. We don't have a choice.
我们别无选择  快点
We don't have a choice. Come on!
上来  上来
Up here! Up here!
尼古拉斯
Nicholas!
尼古拉斯  看着我
Nicholas! Look at me.
看着我  看着我
Hey, look at me! Look at me!
尼古拉斯
Nicholas!
看着我
Look at me!
谢谢你
Thank you.
起来  起来
Come on. Come on.
起来
Come on.
没有烟
There's no smoke.
不代表他们出事了
It doesn't mean they didn't make it.
尸群还在进发
The herd's still coming,
但是小溪应该能减缓它们的速度
but this creek should slow them down some.
格伦
Glenn.
我应该就位了
I'm in place by my best guess.
你们回去了吗
You guys make it back yet?
格伦
Glenn.
托宾  你在吗
Tobin, you there?
达里尔
Daryl?
我在
I'm here.
不会太久的
Won't be long now.
它们快到了
They're almost here.
我会把它们引回你那边
I'll get them going your way again.
怎么样  达里尔
How 'bout that, Daryl?
他要来我们这边了
He's gonna be coming our way.
家那边有枪声
There's gunfire coming from back home.
我们只能忍着  期望他们自己能应付
We gotta sit with it and hope they can handle it.
我觉得他们可以  他们必须可以
I think they can. They have to.
我们要为他们继续前进
We keep going forward for them.
不能因为害怕而回头
Can't turn back 'cause we're afraid.
我们不怕
We ain't afraid.
这是为了他们
This is for them.
计划没完成之前回去  那是为了我们
Going back now before it's done, that'd be for us.
尸群一定马上就到了
The herd has to be almost here.
瑞克
Rick?
不  不  不  不要啊
No, no, no, no, no. No.